{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The plasmid-mediated properties is/are", "opta": "fermentation of lactose", "optb": "production of enterotoxin", "optc": "resistance to antibiotics", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the extracellular medium, DNA-degrading enzymes would likely be to prevent transfer of DNA by", "opta": "conjugal transfer by a self-transmissible plasmid", "optb": "generalized phage transduction", "optc": "natural transformation", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the term used for a segment of DNA with one or more genes in the centre and the two ends carrying inverted repeat sequences of nucleotides?", "opta": "Plasmid", "optb": "Transposon", "optc": "Insertion sequence", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plasmids can be eliminated from a cell by the process known as", "opta": "curing", "optb": "breaking", "optc": "fixing", "optd": "expulsion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recombination of virus genomes occurs", "opta": "by transduction", "optb": "by transription", "optc": "simultaneous infection of a host cell by two viruses with homologous chromosomes", "optd": "by transformation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of recombination that commonly occurs between a pair of homologous DNA sequences is,", "opta": "mutagenic recombination", "optb": "site-specific recombination", "optc": "replicative recombination", "optd": "general recombination", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement describes plasmids?", "opta": "Another name for a protoplast", "optb": "A complex membrane structure that covers the chromosome of bacteria", "optc": "Small, circular DNA molecules that can exist independently of chromosomes commonly found in bacteria", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In lysogeny,", "opta": "a bacteriophage transfers bacterial DNA", "optb": "bacteria take up double stranded DNA from the environment", "optc": "DNA-degrading enzymes in the extracellular medium would stop the process", "optd": "a bacteriophage genome is integrated into the bacterial genome", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A microarray differs from a gene fusion in that, it", "opta": "carries DNA segments from many different genes", "optb": "is not constructed by cloning", "optc": "gives direct measurement of mRNA level", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who discovered transposons (jumping genes)?", "opta": "Abelson", "optb": "Harvey", "optc": "McClintock", "optd": "Griffith", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of plasmid can exist with or without being integrated into the host's chromosome?", "opta": "Medisome", "optb": "Lisosome", "optc": "Lysogen", "optd": "Episome", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main difference between a self-transmissible and a mobilizable plasmid is that the self-transmissible plasmid", "opta": "transfers both strands of the plasmid DNA", "optb": "carries genes encoding the mating apparatus", "optc": "transfers antibiotic resistance genes", "optd": "usually has a transposon inserted into it", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the cause for drug resistance in tuberculosis?", "opta": "Mutation", "optb": "Transduction", "optc": "Transformation", "optd": "Conjugation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transposase gene encodes an enzyme that facilitate", "opta": "viral replication within a genome", "optb": "general recombination", "optc": "site-specific integration of transposable elements", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term used for plasmids possessing both RTF and r determinants is", "opta": "non self-transmissible plasmids", "optb": "non conjugative plasmids", "optc": "conjugative plasmids", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Diagnostic DNA probes have been developed for", "opta": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optb": "Hepatitis B virus", "optc": "Human immunodeficiency virus", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement(s) is/are true in regards to F+ x F- mating events?", "opta": "DNA is transferred from F- to F+ cells", "optb": "DNA is transferred from F+ to F- cells", "optc": "No DNA is transferred because F- cells are unable to perform conjugation", "optd": "No DNA is transferred because F+ cells are unable to perform conjugation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following type of recombination does not require homologous sequences and is important for the integration of viral genomes into bacterial chromosomes?", "opta": "Mutagenic recombimation", "optb": "Site-specific recombination", "optc": "Replicative recombination", "optd": "General recombination", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What information can be generated by interrupted mating experiments?", "opta": "Levels of DNA homology", "optb": "Bacterial genome maps", "optc": "DNA nucleotide sequences", "optd": "Proteomics of the bacteria", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following transport bacterial DNA to other bacteria via bacteriophages?", "opta": "Conjugation", "optb": "Transduction", "optc": "Transformation", "optd": "Translation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When composite transposons are formed", "opta": "a small deletion occurs in the transposase gene of an IS element", "optb": "a small deletion occurs in the transposase gene of an IS element and plasmid is integrated", "optc": "an IS element integrates with another IS element with the help of a plasmid", "optd": "two IS elements integrate into a chromosome with only a small distance separating them", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following plamids do not possess information for self transfer to another cell?", "opta": "Cryptic plasmids", "optb": "Conjugative plasmids", "optc": "Non-conjugative plasmids", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term used for acquisition of naked DNA from its environment and its incorporation in their genome by a bacterium is", "opta": "transformation", "optb": "lysogenic conversion", "optc": "conjugation", "optd": "transduction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is term used for a bacterial cell that is able to take up naked DNA?", "opta": "Complementary", "optb": "Liable", "optc": "Competent", "optd": "Infected", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Penicillin resistance in staphylococci is acquired due to", "opta": "conjugation", "optb": "mutation", "optc": "transformation", "optd": "transduction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plasmid which makes the host more pathogenic is", "opta": "F factors", "optb": "Metabolic plasmid", "optc": "Virulence plasmid", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expression of gene X (which has promoter Px) is to be monitored. A gene fusion construction for carrying this work will", "opta": "have Px but not the rest of the X coding region", "optb": "have the promoter of lacZ or some other reporter gene", "optc": "allow to monitor the expression of all genes with a promoter similar in sequence to Px", "optd": "give the same information as from a microarray", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transducing particles carry only specific portions of the bacterial genome in which of the following transduction?", "opta": "Specialized transduction", "optb": "General transduction", "optc": "Abortive transduction", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The correct term for the transfer of genetic material between bacteria in direct physical contact is", "opta": "conjugation", "optb": "transformation", "optc": "replication", "optd": "transduction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plasmid that carries genes encoding enzymes, which degrade substances such as aromatic compounds, pesticides or sugar are", "opta": "F factors", "optb": "metabolic plasmid", "optc": "virulence plasmid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "R factors involved in plant-microbe interactions are", "opta": "plant proteins", "optb": "bacterial proteins", "optc": "essential for transfer of DNA to plant cells", "optd": "also called opines", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used by microbial genetisists as a tool?", "opta": "Bacteriophage", "optb": "Plasmids", "optc": "Transposable elements", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following type of recombination does not require homologous sequences and is utilized by mobile genetic elements that move about chromosomes?", "opta": "Mutagenic recombimation", "optb": "Site-specific recombination", "optc": "Replicative recombination", "optd": "General recombination", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following term describes the relationship between a virus and host where no new viral particles are produced and the viral genome is replicated along with host chromosome?", "opta": "Lysogeny", "optb": "Lysis", "optc": "Transformation", "optd": "Conjugation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inverted repeat sequences at each end and a gene encoding transposase is contained in which of the following transposable element?", "opta": "Composite transposon", "optb": "Insertion element", "optc": "Virus", "optd": "Plasmid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "F factor plasmids play a major role in", "opta": "conjugation", "optb": "replication", "optc": "transduction", "optd": "trasnscription", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genetic elements carry the genes required for integration into host chromosomes?", "opta": "Replicon", "optb": "Plasmids", "optc": "Transposons", "optd": "Tandons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chromosomal genes, possessing fertility factor is known as", "opta": "R factor", "optb": "F prime factor", "optc": "HFr", "optd": "F factor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement can describe horizontal transfer?", "opta": "The synthesis of protein in RNA", "optb": "The transmission of genetic information from one independent, mature organism to another", "optc": "The transmission of genetic information from parent to offspring", "optd": "The synthesis of RNA from a DNA template", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}